<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>antoineB's blog: Posts tagged 'language'</title>
  <description>antoineB's blog: Posts tagged 'language'</description>
  <link>http://antoineB.github.io/tags/language.html</link>
  <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 13:14:59 UT</lastBuildDate>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 13:14:59 UT</pubDate>
  <ttl>1800</ttl>
  <item>
   <title>Disordered letters</title>
   <link>http://antoineB.github.io/blog/2017/05/07/disordered-letters/?utm_source=language&amp;utm_medium=RSS</link>
   <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:http-antoineB-github-io:-blog-2017-05-07-disordered-letters</guid>
   <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 13:14:59 UT</pubDate>
   <author>antoine</author>
   <description>
&lt;p&gt;It is funny that words with disordered letters can still be read fluently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This little experiment just randomly shuffle every letter in a word and keep the first and last letter untouched. For more go to the pristine idea &lt;a href="http://www.mrc-cbu.cam.ac.uk/people/matt.davis/Cmabrigde/"&gt;Cmabrigde&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;textarea id="source-text"&gt;Enter some text, and click.&lt;/textarea&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;button id="reveal" value="reveal"&gt;Shuffle&lt;/button&gt;

&lt;div id="dump"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="/code/disorderedletters.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some example :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="bs-example"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sciutbrapol Strom Aderna was the fsirt nmead sotrm and fsirt siruopbatcl cycnloe of the 2007 Aiatlntc huinrcare saeson. Six people dwnored as a rueslt of the sotrm. It arose out of an eraoptctiarxl sotrm taht atetnaid huinrcare-frcoe wdins on May 7, three and a half wekes berofe the oafcifil satrt of the huinrcare saeson. A non-tiarcopl low deepleovd on May 9 aobut 150 melis (240 km) nsraeohtt of Dtyonaa Bcaeh, Fidlroa. It wkeenaed to a siruopbatcl deisropsen the nxet day wilhe rniianmeg nerlay snirttoaay, and the Ntaianol Hnrcaruie Ceentr duiitesocnnd aeirdvosis erlay on May 11. Aderna was the fsirt pre-saeson sotrm scine Taricpol Strom Ana in April 2003 and the fsirt Aiatlntc nmead sotrm in May scine Taricpol Strom Aelrne in 1981&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Woo this is quite hard to grasp in fact. There is a lot of long non-ultra-commun words, the text is fact focus resulting in low number of words per contexts and the Names are shuffle as well (Andrea, Florida).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="bs-example"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Subtropical Storm Andrea was the first named storm and first subtropical cyclone of the 2007 Atlantic hurricane season. Six people drowned as a result of the storm. It arose out of an extratropical storm that attained hurricane-force winds on May 7, three and a half weeks before the official start of the hurricane season. A non-tropical low developed on May 9 about 150 miles (240 km) northeast of Daytona Beach, Florida. It weakened to a subtropical depression the next day while remaining nearly stationary, and the National Hurricane Center discontinued advisories early on May 11. Andrea was the first pre-season storm since Tropical Storm Ana in April 2003 and the first Atlantic named storm in May since Tropical Storm Arlene in 1981&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a more easy read with text from a novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="bs-example"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;When one whiess to paly the wit, he semoeitms weadnrs a ltltie from the truth. I have not been agetltoehr hsnoet in waht I have told you aoubt the llhtiaegpmrs. And I raezlie that I run the risk of gvniig a fsale idea of our pnleat to thsoe who do not know it. Men occupy a very small pcale uopn the Eatrh. If the two bilioln ihbtianntas who ploepe its sfrcaue were all to sntad uprghit and smoahwet cweordd teotehgr, as they do for smoe big puiblc asemlsby, they cuold eailsy be put itno one puiblc sraque ttewny meils lnog and ttewny meils wdie. All hiaumtny cuold be pelid up on a small Paiifcc ielst.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="bs-example"&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;When one wishes to play the wit, he sometimes wanders a little from the truth. I have not been altogether honest in what I have told you about the lamplighters. And I realize that I run the risk of giving a false idea of our planet to those who do not know it. Men occupy a very small place upon the Earth. If the two billion inhabitants who people its surface were all to stand upright and somewhat crowded together, as they do for some big public assembly, they could easily be put into one public square twenty miles long and twenty miles wide. All humanity could be piled up on a small Pacific islet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example the pain points where lamplighters it just look like a mess even knowing it is lamplighters, and islet can&amp;rsquo;t find it even with the strong context &amp;ldquo;small pacific&amp;rdquo; which focus me on the search &amp;ldquo;isle&amp;rdquo; but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the word islet so it was more difficult to infer it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>